<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.virinvictus.atrium</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>

  <name>Atrium</name>
  <summary>Local-first GTD task manager with a native GNOME design</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Atrium is a native GNOME task manager that fuses Things 3 clarity with
      OmniFocus depth via a mode switch over a shared local-first data store.
      Pick Simple Mode for what-am-I-doing-right-now; switch to Builder Mode
      when you want full GTD review, deferral, sequential projects, and
      forecast. Same data, two surfaces, no migration.
    </p>
    <p>
      Storage is one SQLite file at $XDG_DATA_HOME/atrium/atrium.db, written
      by a single dedicated worker thread so the UI never blocks on I/O. The
      schema is the OmniFocus superset on day one — Simple Mode hides the
      Builder fields, it doesn't lack them. An optional Org-mode vault
      mirrors the database as round-trippable .org files so your data stays
      portable to Emacs, Logseq, or a pile of files in a git repo.
    </p>
    <p>Simple Mode features (v0.1):</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Inbox · Today · Upcoming · Anytime · Someday · Logbook</li>
      <li>Areas → Projects → Tasks hierarchy with multi-tag</li>
      <li>Distinct When (scheduled-for) and Deadline dates</li>
      <li>Quick Entry global modal (Ctrl+Alt+Space)</li>
      <li>FTS5-backed search with filter expressions (tag:, is:, due:)</li>
      <li>Multi-select bulk operations with undo (Ctrl+Z)</li>
      <li>Find-as-you-type sidebar filter (Ctrl+L)</li>
      <li>Keyboard-first — every common op bindable, mouse optional</li>
      <li>Drag-reorder rows; drag tasks onto projects to file them</li>
      <li>Local-first — no network, no telemetry, no accounts</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.virinvictus.atrium.desktop</launchable>
  <icon type="stock">io.github.virinvictus.atrium</icon>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/VirInvictus/Atrium</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/VirInvictus/Atrium/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/VirInvictus/Atrium</url>

  <developer id="io.github.virinvictus">
    <name>Brandon LaRocque</name>
  </developer>

  <provides>
    <binary>atrium</binary>
  </provides>

  <categories>
    <category>Office</category>
    <category>ProjectManagement</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>todo</keyword>
    <keyword>tasks</keyword>
    <keyword>gtd</keyword>
    <keyword>omnifocus</keyword>
    <keyword>things</keyword>
    <keyword>org-mode</keyword>
    <keyword>productivity</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <recommends>
    <display_length compare="ge">768</display_length>
    <internet>offline-only</internet>
  </recommends>

  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </supports>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#F4F1EA</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#1A1D21</color>
  </branding>

  <!-- TODO: add <screenshots> section once a release build is ready to
       capture against. Phase 9 task. -->

  <releases>
    <release version="0.6.5" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>atrium-cli perspective write side — closes the gap
           that the only way to create or convert a saved
           perspective from the shell was via direct SQL.
           Three new sub-subcommands: <code>perspective create
           NAME --filter EXPR …</code>, <code>perspective edit
           NAME …</code> (with --rename / --filter / --icon /
           --renderer / --columns), and <code>perspective
           delete NAME</code>. Name lookup is case-insensitive
           exact on write paths so a typo can't accidentally
           edit the wrong row. <code>--renderer board</code>
           requires <code>--columns</code> on create; on edit,
           <code>--columns</code> alone updates an existing
           board's column list in place. The regression
           ship-gate now exercises the full create → board
           conversion → list conversion → delete round-trip.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.4" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>Slice D2 — the Agenda canonical page. Org-mode-style
           chronological view that groups open tasks into
           Overdue / Today / Tomorrow / This Week / Next Week
           sections. Tasks farther out live in Forecast; tasks
           without a time anchor (no scheduled, no deadline)
           don't appear. The Overdue heading is rendered in red
           so urgency reads at a glance. Each row shows title +
           date chip + project + tag pills, and clicking opens
           the Inspector. Available alongside Forecast and
           Review in the Builder-mode sidebar.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.3" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>Kanban drag-drop between columns. The kanban is no
           longer read-only — drag a task row from one column
           to another and its tag set is rewritten so the
           grouper buckets it under the new column. The
           rewrite removes the source column tag, adds the
           destination column tag (if not already present),
           and preserves any non-column tags. Dropping on the
           trailing "Other" column just removes the source
           column tag. Pure-Rust tag-rewrite logic in
           atrium-core (eight unit tests) so the GUI stays
           a thin GTK4 DnD adapter on top.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.2" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>Perspective renderer dialog — closes the v0.6.0 gap
           that the only way to make a Perspective render as a
           kanban was direct SQL or the test fixture. Right-
           clicking a Perspective row in the sidebar now opens
           a "Configure renderer…" dialog: pick List or Board,
           edit the column list (comma-separated tag names),
           save. The active perspective re-renders immediately
           when the worker emits the library-changes delta.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.1" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>Kanban polish — board rows now show a metadata line
           with the project name, the most-relevant date
           (deadline if set, else scheduled, else Someday), and
           tag pills using the same Pango-coloured markup the
           regular task list uses. The completion checkbox is
           interactive: clicking it toggles the task via the
           worker, same as the rest of the app. Tasks with no
           metadata stay tight — the secondary line is
           suppressed entirely rather than rendering empty.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.0" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>Slice D1 GUI — saved Perspectives whose renderer is
           <code>"board"</code> now render as a horizontal kanban
           layout in the main window instead of a flat list.
           Each column is a tag (leftmost match wins, trailing
           "Other" bucket for tasks that don't match any
           configured column), and clicking a task row opens it
           in the Inspector. Read-only at v0.6.0: drag-drop
           between columns, in-board completion toggles, and a
           board-renderer editing dialog all follow in a sibling
           patch — for now, moving tasks between columns is
           <code>atrium-cli edit ID --tag X --remove-tag Y</code>
           or the Inspector's tag editor. Same grouping engine
           the v0.5.4 <code>atrium-cli kanban</code> subcommand
           uses, so the GUI and CLI stay in lockstep.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.4" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>Slice D1 foundation — saved Perspectives can render
           as kanban boards. v0.5.4 ships the headless engine:
           a renderer parser, a tag-axis grouping helper, and
           a complete <code>atrium-cli kanban NAME</code>
           subcommand that exercises the renderer end-to-end
           from the shell. The GUI consumer lands in v0.6.0.
           Three locked rules keep the kanban tight:
           leftmost-match-wins per task, an unconditional
           "Other" trailing column for tasks that don't match
           any configured column, and case-insensitive tag
           matching to mirror the rest of the search engine.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.3" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>SQL-translation evaluator for the Calibre-style search
           expression language — the fourth v0.6.x carryover off
           the deferred list. Queries that map cleanly onto SQL
           (boolean composition, bare text, state predicates,
           title/note/tag matches, date comparisons / ranges,
           numeric estimated comparisons) now execute at the
           SQLite layer instead of pulling every row into memory.
           Anything not yet expressible in SQL — regex
           (<code>tag:~</code>), fuzzy (<code>tag:?</code>),
           sequential-project state, the composite
           <code>is:today</code> / <code>is:upcoming</code>
           family — falls back to the in-memory evaluator. The
           two paths are pinned to identical behaviour by 21
           parity integration tests. Atrium-cli wires the
           fast-path for v1; the GUI search-bar follows in a
           sibling patch.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.2" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>FTS5 bm25 + recency ranking on bare-text searches —
           the third v0.6.x carryover off the deferred list.
           Searching for a freeform word (in the search bar or
           via <code>atrium-cli search milk</code>) now ranks
           the matches by FTS5's <code>bm25</code> blended with
           a 30-day half-life recency factor. Stronger matches
           and freshly-touched tasks rise to the top instead of
           every result coming back in task-position order.
           Skipped automatically when the query carries an
           explicit <code>sort:</code> modifier — power users
           keep their pinned ordering.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.1" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>Patch release. Three small, coupled fixes the v0.5.0
           ship-gate hadn't been wide enough to catch:
           the atrium-cli runtime nesting panic on every write
           subcommand (Cannot start a runtime from within a runtime),
           a broken-pipe panic when piping output into
           <code>head</code> or other early-closing consumers,
           and a regression-script step that exercises
           atrium-cli end-to-end against a fixture database
           so the next ship-gate catches the same shape of bug.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.0" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>A meaty minor — fifteen post-v0.4.0 patches rolled
           together into one shippable boundary.
           Phase 15.5 deferred-list closed: state predicates,
           <code>sort:</code> modifier, fuzzy <code>?</code> match,
           search history, and an operator-reference popover.
           Architectural extraction: the search engine now lives
           as its own workspace crate <code>atrium-search</code>,
           and a complete headless CLI <code>atrium-cli</code>
           ships alongside the GTK binary — every non-GUI surface
           is now exercisable from the shell.
           Phase 15.75 visual polish (partial): visual rhythm
           pass, per-area accent stripes, canonical-list icon
           tinting, About-dialog icon resolution.
           Closes the v0.4.0 deferred bug list.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 15.5 — Calibre-powered search. The search bar's
           filter language grew from a flat <code>tag:foo is:open</code>
           shape into a full Calibre-style expression grammar:
           boolean operators (AND / OR / NOT), parens grouping,
           comparison operators on date and numeric fields
           (<code>due:&gt;today</code>, <code>estimated:&gt;=30</code>),
           inclusive ranges (<code>due:2026-05-01..2026-05-31</code>),
           date keywords (<code>thisweek</code>, <code>lastmonth</code>,
           <code>5daysago</code>), state predicates
           (<code>is:overdue</code>, <code>is:repeating</code>,
           <code>is:tagged</code>), and Calibre-style match modifiers
           (<code>tag:x</code> substring, <code>tag:=x</code> exact,
           <code>tag:~x</code> regex, <code>tag:true</code>/false
           existence). Saved Perspectives inherit the new grammar
           for free since they store filter expressions verbatim.
           The full operator reference lives in spec §4.3.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Visual polish pass. Tag colours land — six-swatch picker
           in the tag editor, coloured dots in the sidebar, coloured
           pills on every task row. Task rows light up gently on
           hover; completing a task gives the checkbox a brief
           celebratory pop. Per-list empty states get warmer copy
           and the right icon (Someday gets a moon, no more weird
           house glyph). Project headings now show the area
           breadcrumb so you know where you are in the hierarchy.
           The Builder Mode Inspector pane reads as its own sheet
           with a subtle left border.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.2" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Audit-pass bug fixes. Filter typos in the search bar (or in
           a saved Perspective) now surface a toast instead of silently
           no-op-ing — type <code>tga:work</code> by mistake and you'll
           see "Unknown filter" rather than empty results. New empty-
           library hint at the bottom of the sidebar nudges first-run
           users toward "New Project" when there's nothing in their
           library yet. Inbox tasks now read "Inbox" in the
           Area › Project context chip on Today and similar views,
           rather than rendering blank. Screen-reader experience
           improved: count badges now announce as "5 open tasks"
           instead of bare "5".</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.1" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Two task-row fixes. Adding or removing a tag in the
           per-task editor now updates the row's tag pill in place
           instead of leaving stale text. And task rows on Today,
           Inbox, Anytime, and other cross-list views now show an
           "Area › Project" chip so you can place each task in your
           hierarchy at a glance.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.2.0" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Builder Mode milestone — Phase 15 lands repeating tasks
           with full RFC 5545 RRULE support. Set a repeat in the
           Inspector (Daily / Weekly / Monthly / Yearly preset, or a
           custom RRULE string), pick the Org-mode behavior — Cumulative
           (the default — spawn the next instance after now),
           From-completion-date (anchor on when you finished),
           or Always-shift (basic). When you complete a repeating
           task, Atrium spawns the next instance in place with all
           dates shifted, tags carried forward, and project / parent
           preserved. Backwards-compatible <code>0003_repeat_mode.sql</code>
           migration adds the mode column to <code>task</code>.</p>
        <p>v0.2.0 also runs the sanctioned major-bump maintenance
           pass: dead Builder-stub helper removed, four duplicated
           dummy-task test helpers consolidated behind a new
           <code>atrium-core</code> <code>test-support</code> feature
           gate. Spec §4.4 schema-freeze rule formally amended to
           "no breaking mid-v0.1 changes" — purely-additive new tables
           and columns are now allowed.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.17" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 14 — saved Perspectives. Save the current search bar
           query as a named view from the primary menu, and it lands
           in a dedicated Perspectives section in the Builder sidebar.
           Each perspective re-runs its filter expression every time
           it's opened, so it stays current with the underlying tasks.
           Right-click a perspective to rename or delete it. Adds a
           backwards-compatible <code>0002_perspectives.sql</code>
           migration; existing databases upgrade in place.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.16" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 13 — Review queue. Builder Mode's GTD discipline:
           projects with a configured review interval surface in
           the Review sidebar entry when their last review is older
           than the interval allows. Each card shows the project
           title, area, how stale the review is, and a Mark Reviewed
           button that stamps the timestamp and drops the row out
           of the queue. The Phase 10 Review stub is gone.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.15" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Fix: fast double-clicks now reliably trigger inline title
           edit. GtkListView's internal click gesture was claiming
           the event sequence on fast doubles to fire its own
           activate signal, which blocked our row-level gesture
           from seeing the second release. Now listening to
           GtkListView::activate directly so the path GTK uses
           internally for double-click activation is the path we
           use too. The per-row gesture stays in place to catch
           slower doubles that fall outside GTK's window.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.14" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Fix: double-click → inline title edit was firing the
           edit but the editor was closing before users saw it.
           Cause: the click event was still propagating when our
           gesture's handler ran; GtkListView's internal selection
           handler grabbed focus on the row *after* we'd grabbed
           focus on the entry, triggering the entry's focus-leave
           handler which committed and closed the editor. Deferred
           the edit-start to an idle callback so it runs after the
           event settles, and our grab_focus is the last word.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.13" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Double-click hardening: 700 ms time window widened to
           800 ms, plus the gesture now bails out when the row is
           already in edit mode. Stops fast double-clicks from
           bouncing the cursor and resetting the entry text after
           the editor opens.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.12" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Fix: double-clicking a task row now reliably enters
           inline title edit. The previous detection used GTK's
           built-in n_press counter which only matches clicks
           inside the system's gtk-double-click-time setting
           (~400 ms by default) — too tight for natural
           trackpad double-clicks. Replaced with our own 700 ms
           time-window detection so the gesture matches user
           intent rather than the system threshold.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.11" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Diagnostic build for the double-click-not-firing report.
           The per-row activate gesture moved from Bubble to
           Capture propagation phase so it fires before the parent
           GtkListItemWidget's selection-handling can consume the
           event. Plus debug-level tracing on both the gesture
           handler and start_edit_on_row so the trace output tells
           us exactly which step is failing.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.10" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Double-click a task row now enters inline title edit
           (same surface as F2). Single click still selects and
           holds focus. The Inspector dialog stays accessible via
           Ctrl+I and right-click → Edit Details… — double-click
           is the lighter "just rename this" path. Things-3 idiom.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.9" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Fix: double-clicking a task in Simple Mode now reliably
           opens the modal Inspector dialog. open_inspector_for was
           still reading the GSettings mode string directly, which
           v0.1.6 caught as unreliable across Settings wrapper
           instances. Migrated every same-frame mode read to the
           synchronous Cell tracker that apply_mode writes to
           first; the only GSettings reads that remain are the
           startup initial-mode and the safety-net observer's
           callback, both of which flow into apply_mode and
           populate the Cell.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.8" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>The bulk-action toolbar above the task list now reveals
           only when 2 or more rows are selected. Single-row
           selection had the row checkbox + Delete key + Ctrl+I
           covering everything, so the toolbar's Complete and
           Delete buttons were just redundant duplicates of those.
           The toolbar still appears for true multi-select bulk
           ops.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.7" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Fix: switching to Builder Mode via the menu now reliably
           shows the side pane on the same frame as the click. The
           window's GSettings change observer wasn't firing on the
           process's own writes — likely two separate Settings
           wrappers and the dconf backend not crossing the changed
           signal between them. The menu action now calls
           window.apply_mode directly after persisting the GSetting,
           and the observer stays as a safety net for external
           writes (dconf-editor and similar).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.6" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Fix: the Inspector side pane now reliably populates when
           you select a task in Builder Mode. The v0.1.5 mode-gate
           in the selection-changed handler was reading the GSettings
           string directly, which sometimes returned a stale value
           on the same frame as a mode flip. Replaced with a
           synchronous Cell tracker that apply_mode writes before
           any other work happens. Plus debug-level tracing on every
           branch of the pane-refresh path so the next bug report
           comes with data.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.5" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Fix: the Inspector side pane now reliably hides when
           switching from Builder Mode back to Simple. The
           OverlaySplitView's show-sidebar property alone wasn't
           sufficient — apply_mode now also hides the pane host
           explicitly and clears its content, and the selection-
           changed handler bails out in Simple Mode so it can't
           repopulate the editor for an invisible pane.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.4" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Fix: Ctrl+I, double-click, and right-click → Edit Details
           now consistently open the editor in Builder Mode by
           routing the targeted task into the side pane and grabbing
           keyboard focus on its title row. The v0.1.1 design call
           that made these no-ops in Builder was wrong — the user's
           mental model of Ctrl+I is "get me into the editor for
           this task," not "open another editor on top of one I'm
           already looking at." Simple Mode keeps opening the modal
           dialog as before.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.3" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 12 — Forecast view. Builder Mode's calendar-axis
           layout: a scrollable column of day cards over the next 30
           days, each showing scheduled / deadlined / defer-ending
           tasks with reason chips. Today's card gets an accent
           border; an Overdue pseudo-block at the top surfaces
           past-due open tasks. Drag a task between day cards to
           reschedule it. The Phase 10 Forecast stub is gone.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.2" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 11 — defer dates and sequential project rendering.
           The Inspector (modal + side pane) gains a working
           "Defer until" date picker; tasks deferred to a future
           date drop out of Today and Anytime until the date
           crosses. In a sequential project, only the first
           incomplete task renders at full opacity; the rest dim
           with a `.queued` CSS class. Sidebar project badges in
           Builder Mode show the *available* count (1 for sequential,
           N for parallel) instead of the raw open count. The Phase
           10 placeholder for `estimated_minutes` becomes a live
           SpinRow that dispatches to the worker.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.1" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 10 — Builder Mode UI shell. The mode switch becomes
           real: the primary menu Mode → Builder toggle now reveals
           an Inspector side pane on the right (auto-saving as you
           edit), Builder-only sidebar entries (Forecast, Review,
           Perspectives) appear as stub placeholders pointing at the
           phases that fill them in, and project pages gain a
           Sequential toggle and Review interval picker. Per spec
           §3.1 mode-as-view, no DB work happens on mode switch —
           enforced by the new mode-flip snapshot integration test.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-05-07" type="stable">
      <description>
        <p>First public release. Simple Mode is feature-complete:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Inbox · Today · Upcoming · Anytime · Someday · Logbook</li>
          <li>Areas → Projects → Tasks hierarchy with multi-tag</li>
          <li>Scheduled (When) and Deadline distinction; Today picks up
              both overdue items and the next 7 days of deadlines</li>
          <li>Quick Entry global capture (Ctrl+Alt+Space) with inline
              #tag / @today / @deadline syntax</li>
          <li>FTS5-backed search with filter expressions
              (tag:NAME · is:open|done|overdue · due:today)</li>
          <li>Inspector and tag editor for the full per-task fieldset</li>
          <li>Multi-select with bulk Complete / Delete and Ctrl+Z undo</li>
          <li>Find-as-you-type sidebar filter (Ctrl+L)</li>
          <li>Keyboard-first — every common op bound, mouse optional</li>
          <li>Local-first storage at $XDG_DATA_HOME/atrium/atrium.db
              (single-writer SQLite worker, WAL mode); no network,
              no telemetry, no accounts</li>
          <li>High-legibility accessibility toggle (Atkinson Hyperlegible)</li>
        </ul>
        <p>The schema is the OmniFocus superset on day one — Builder
           Mode (v0.2) will expose the columns Simple Mode hides; no
           migration on mode switch.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.38" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>Today filter widens to include upcoming-deadline heads-up.
           Spec §4.2 picks up a `today + N` deadline window (default
           7 days), so a task with a deadline approaching surfaces in
           Today before it's actually due — the behaviour Things 3
           users expect. Earlier versions left future-deadlined tasks
           buried in Anytime until the deadline date arrived.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.37" date="2026-05-07">
      <description>
        <p>UI bugsweep before v0.1.0. Inspector + tag editor switch from
           free-standing windows to in-window AdwDialogs (the v0.0.36 form
           rendered as a transparent overlay because the parent window
           bled through). Task rows replace GtkEditableLabel with a
           Label/Entry stack so single-clicks on the title no longer
           hijack the row's selection / Inspector-open path. Esc moves
           from a window-global accel onto the task list's shortcut
           controller — typing in any entry no longer silently clears
           the multi-selection. Date pills stop ellipsising (no more
           "May" rows). Documentation refresh in CLAUDE.md and keymap.md.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.23" date="2026-05-06">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 8a — typography polish + completion fade. Inter cv11/ss01 on
           UI labels, tabular figures audit, surface-by-surface size/weight
           pass, opacity fade for completed task rows.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.22" date="2026-05-06">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 7f — full keyboard map. Ctrl+Z invokes the active undo
           toast; F2 starts inline editing on the focused task row.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.21" date="2026-05-06">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 7e — find-as-you-type sidebar. GtkSearchEntry above the row
           list filters areas, projects, and tags; Ctrl+L focuses it.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.20" date="2026-05-06">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 7d — search filter expressions. tag:, is:, due: clauses mix
           with freeform text in the search bar.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.19" date="2026-05-06">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 7c — multi-select with Ctrl+Click / Shift+Click / Ctrl+A,
           bulk Complete and Delete actions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.18" date="2026-05-06">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 7b — undo for toggle-complete and delete-task via 6 s
           AdwToast.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.17" date="2026-05-06">
      <description>
        <p>Phase 7a — FTS5-backed search bar (Ctrl+F).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.0" date="2026-05-04">
      <description>
        <p>Pre-implementation — the contract, public framing, and metadata
           land before any code. Phases 0 through 6 wire up the workspace,
           data layer, UI shell, and Simple Mode core (Inbox/Today, Areas,
           Projects, Tags, Quick Entry).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
